<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Some considerations concerning the high-court of Chancery and the ordinance made for the regulation and limitation of that court.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1657</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 20 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 7 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A60770</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S4482A</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R221575</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99832872</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99832872</idno>
            <idno type="VID">37347</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A60770)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 37347)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 2061:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Some considerations concerning the high-court of Chancery and the ordinance made for the regulation and limitation of that court.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 10 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>[s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Printed in the year, 1657.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>England and Wales. --  Court of Chancery --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Political corruption --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:37347:1"/>
            <p>SOME CONSIDERATIONS CONCERNING The High-Court OF CHANCERY, AND THE
ORDINANCE MADE For the Regulation and Limitation OF THAT COURT.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed in the Year, 1657.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:37347:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:37347:2" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>SOME CONSIDERATIONS CONCERNING THE High Court of Chancery,
<hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THe Author of this Diſcourſe, is a man utterly a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gainſt the
licentious publiſhing of Pamphlets, as being very ſenſible of the danger
enſuing by it, and profeſſeth a diſſability of compoſing any thing
worth owning; But having been a ſuitor and a ſufferer in the high Court of
Chancery for very many years, even above the common age of man, and having
found by expe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rience the former iniquity in the courſe of Practice in that
Court, and the great benefit and advantage of that moſt excellent Ordinance,
made by his Highneſſe, and his moſt Honourable Councel, for the
regulation and limitation of that Court, and being informed of ſome ſtrong
endea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vours uſed to repeal and null that Ordinance, doth crave leave for the
publication of theſe his Obſervations, that ſo the people of this Nation,
who have, or ſhall have occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of ſuit in that Court, may be informed
of the benefit they have, or may receive by the Ordinance: In which he a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>meth at nothing but the publique good
and welfare of the Nation.</p>
            <p>Amongſt the many things that time and corruption had made the
object of Reformation in this Nation, nothing had more need of a Regulation and
Reforming, then the high Court of Chancery, which was formerly, and
eſpecially of later times, ſo chargeable to Sutors in the proſecution,
and defence of their Cauſes, and ſo corrupt and uncertain in the practiſe
thereof; that in ſtead of a Sanctuary to the op<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>preſſed, it was become a
moſt intollerable burthen to the<pb n="2" facs="tcp:37347:3"/>Nation, and
(notwithſtanding all addreſſes to the long Parliament) ſo continued,
untill the Parliament which be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gan in the year 1653. (which was compoſed of
perſons, though perhaps not very learned Stateſmen, yet doubtleſſe men
of very good and honeſt intentions, and very ſenſible of the burthens of
the Nation.) By whom it was voted to be taken away. But that Parliament
diſſolving, it pleaſed his Highneſſe to continue that Court, it being
indeed of very excellent uſe for the Nation, and without which it can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not
ſubſiſt, as the Common Law now ſtands, and both it and the Common Law
being challenged by the people, as their indubitate birthright.</p>
            <p>Yet notwithſtanding his Highneſſe was pleaſed to appoint
divers of the Long robe to conſider of a way for the regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation and
reformation of that Court, but they (for what reaſon I know not) did not
effect that good work, ſo much longed for, and needed by the people of this
Land.</p>
            <p>Whereupon his Highneſſe by advice of his moſt Honou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rable
Councel (notwithſtanding the other great and im<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>portant buſineſſes for
the Government and ſafety of the Nation lay on them) did make an Ordinance
for the Regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation and limitation of that Court. A better nor more ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curate
and excellent, this Land and Nation never ſaw, which after much ſtrugling,
almoſt a year after the making there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, was put in execution; whereat, as no
good man could take exceptions, ſo none but thoſe concerned in point of a
corrupt intereſt, could or did ſpeak againſt it: and it may be well
obſerved, that ſince the ſame was put in execution, no complaints have
been heard againſt it from the people, for whoſe good and eaſe chiefly
the ſame was made.</p>
            <p>Yet nevertheleſſe, ſince the beginni<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>g of this preſent Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, ſome unneceſſary,
burthenſom Officers, which either had part of their former unconſcionable
gain taken from them, or elſe their Offices ſet aſide, as
unneceſſary, have been indefatigable in their endeavours, to get that
moſt excellent Ordinance repealed.</p>
            <p>And a Committee of Parliament being app<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>inted for the view of the Ordinances made by his
Highneſſe in the int<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>r<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vall
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:37347:3"/>of Parliaments, that Ordinance was moſt eſpecially
ſtruck at, through the clamours of thoſe late unneceſſary Officers of
that Court, who aimed not at the good of their Country, but their own private
unconſcionable gain.</p>
            <p>Nevertheleſs it pleaſed the Parliament to referre the mat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter
to another Committee to amend that Regulation ſetled by the Ordinance (if
they ſaw cauſe) and to ſend for par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties Papers, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> which
Committee accordingly meeting the Attornies by command, and the late ſix
Clerks atten<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded them; where the Councel for the ſix Clerks was heard in a
moſt tedious and impertinent diſcourſe, and the Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neys receiving then
a command from that Committee, to prepare their reaſons in writing, and to
ſet forth wherein the Ordinance was good or bad for the people, and a very
ſhort time given them to that purpoſe: They (as I have heard) accordingly
prepared their Reaſons, and attended to have preſented them to the
Committee.</p>
            <p>But the Committee not afterwards meeting, the Attor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies Reaſons
could not be preſented to them; and the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinance being ſince by Act of
Parliament only to continue during the ſitting of this Parliament, it is much
feared that it is the drift of thoſe perſons who are left out as
unneceſſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Officers in that Court, to improve their intereſt, and uſe
all endeavours to hinder any further conſideration of the Ordinance by the
Parliament, ſo that thereby the Or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dinance may fall to the ground, and the
old way of Practice in that Court be ſet up again, to the great prejudice of
the Commonwealth.</p>
            <p>It therefore much concerneth all honeſt well minded people of
this Nation, that they make their humble ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dreſſes to the Parliament
minding them, that before the end thereof, they tak<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1+ letters">
                  <desc>•…</desc>
               </gap> the Ordinance into conſideration;
and that what ſhall appear to be good therein may be confirmed, and what
ſhall be found therein to be ſhort for the intended welfare of the Nation,
may be ſupplied, and what appeareth to them to be any way diſcommodious to
the people (if any ſuch thing there be) may be amen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded; that ſo, ſo good
a conſtitution may not fall to the<pb n="4" facs="tcp:37347:4"/>ground unregarded, which
hath with ſo much delibera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion and reſolution, been appointed for the good
and eaſe of the people.</p>
            <p>And to the end the people may be the better informed of the
advantage they have and ſhall receive by that Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, it were to be
wiſhed that thoſe Reaſons that the Attornies or Clerks of the Chancery,
had provided to be preſented to the Committee of Parliament, were made
publique. But as there is juſt cauſe to fear that in them the Arrow was not
drawn to the head (in their compoſing, there being a great oppoſition, as I
have been informed, even amongſt themſelves) ſo without doubt they are
now ſuppreſſed through the influence and awe the before men<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioned
unneceſſary Officers have over the abject and pri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vate ſpirits of the
preſent Attornies.</p>
            <p>The Ordinance in the firſt place provides a convenient number of
Attornies, who are to ſolicite and manage the Clients Cauſe for 3<hi rend="sup">s</hi> 4<hi rend="sup">d</hi> a
Term, which Fee was formerly received by the ſix Clerks, for doing nothing at
all for the benefit of the Client, who was forced either to imploy a Solicitor
to manage his buſineſſe, to his great loſſe, or elſe to manage it
himſelf, whereby his Cauſe often times miſcarried, through either his own
or his Solicitors ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norance.</p>
            <p>For the other matters formerly done by the ſix Clerks, it is by
Ordinance provided to be done by three chief Clerks, who have Fees amounting to
500<hi rend="sup">lb</hi> a year a piece, which is a competent allowance for their labour, they
being to file the Pleadings and Records, to have an inſpection upon the
Attornies, to make Certificates of matters re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferred to them by the Court,
touching the regularity of proceedings, to ſet down Cauſes for hearing, and
tax coſt: all which is better done by them, then ever it was done by the
ſix Clerks; ſaving that the Chief Clerks, who were three of the late ſix
Clerks, are ſomewhat ſullen, and do not in ſome things purſue the
Ordinance according to their duty.</p>
            <p>Now this, and the abatement of the Fees, are the things
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:37347:4"/>that are ſtruck at by the late ſix Clerks, and other
uſeleſſe Officers, whoſe pretence is, that their places, and the old
Fees are their Freehold, and therefore ought not to be taken from them; that
they purchaſed their places, and that they are of great antiquity.</p>
            <p>As to their Freehold, I wonder whoſe Freehold their places had
been, if the little Parliament had paſſed an Act for taking away the Court,
as the former Parliament did for taking away the Star-Chamber, and high
Commiſſion Court, and this Parliament the Court of Wards, in which divers
as uſefull Officers as they, without reparation, loſt their places, as much
their Freehold, as the ſix Clerks, and alſo purchaſed at as dear rates.
But the ſix Clerks may ſee their own unjuſt practice juſtly retaliated
on them, that uſed at their pleaſures, without cauſe, to turn out the
Clerks bred up there, into the wide world to ſtarve, if they had nothing
elſe to live upon.</p>
            <p>And for their Antiquity, It is true, there was one At<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>torney, and
but one at the firſt inſtitution of the Court, then as the buſineſſe
increaſed, two were added, and then three more, in which number they by
bribery a long time ſtood a grand cheat to the people, and a crying
oppreſſion over the Clerks, who really did the buſineſſe of the
Court. And ſince ſix Clerks cannot poſſibly perform the Office of
Attornies, and perform the buſineſſe of the Client, it is hoped that it
is no more injuſtice to increaſe the number of Attornies now, then it was
in times paſt.</p>
            <p>And I hope the ſix Clerks will be ſo ingenious, as to
confeſſe, that beſides the impoſſibility for them to ſolicite the
Clients Cauſes, not one nor all of them together, are able to do any thing
belonging to an Attorney or Clerk to do, <hi>viz.</hi> to draw all ſpecial
Writs, Commiſſions, Decrees, Diſmiſſions, and to make and write all
other Writs, and copy Records. This being true, why ſhould they be paid for
what they neither do, or know how to do, or mono<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>polize the place of an
Attorney, which they cannot execute.</p>
            <p>Thus I hope it is apparent that their removal is no injuſtice,
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:37347:5"/>and that the increaſe of the number of Attorneys is a
benefit to the Commonwealth; and there is no doubt, but if the Ordinance, as to
the Officers, Clerks and Attornies of the Court, were put more ſtrictly and
duly in execution, it would be of admirable benefit to all Sutors, and thoſe
that are ſued in that Court. For, the tediouſneſſe of ſuits, is by
the Ordinance very well provided againſt, as alſo divers Writs, as
Subpena's to make a better anſwer, and to rejoyn are taken away: as
likewiſe, whereas before, when wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſes were examined in Court, or by
Commiſſion <hi>ex parte,</hi> it was ordinarily two or three Terms before
publication could paſſe; now it is provided in the Ordinance to paſſe
in a week.</p>
            <p>Likewiſe the making of all Writs open, cannot but be a great
ſatisfaction to the people, they being thereby ena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bled to ſee whether the
Writ have any miſtake in it or not; whereas while they were cloſe, the
Client was often put to a deal of fruitleſſe charge, eſpecially in the
Commiſſions, to examine Witneſſes, as I my ſelf have found by
experi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence: And likewiſe it is left by the Ordinance at the Clients liberty
to execute a Commiſſion in any place, which with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out doubt is, and may be
of good conſequence, for the amicable ending of ſuits, eſpecially if the
Commiſſioners be men of judgement and integrity.</p>
            <p>Alſo the frequent renewing of Commiſſions, tending only to
delay, is well provided againſt by the Ordinance, and the Defendants having a
duplicate, is of advantage to him, eſpecially in caſes where his
witneſſes are ancient and ſickly.</p>
            <p>Likewiſe the granting of Injunctions meerly upon the courſe of
the Court, <hi>viz.</hi> upon the Defendants taking a Commiſſion to
anſwer, ſitting in contempt, or making an inſufficient anſwer, was
heretofore a great grievance to the Nation, but very well provided by the
Ordinance, to be granted only upon ſound and ſatisfactory grounds.</p>
            <p>And alſo whereas heretofore a Defendant could hardly put in any
Anſwer, but the Plaintiff would put in excepti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons to it, which were referred
to a Maſter, who uſually<pb n="7" facs="tcp:37347:5"/>favoured the Plaintiff, and ſo
the Client was put to a dou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble charge: Now by the Ordinance it is provided,
that only the Maſter of the Rolls ſhall hear them; and the moſt
ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nourable and judicious Gentleman, the preſent Maſter of the Rolls, hath
ſo impartially heard thoſe matters, that it is believed the putters in of
frivolous exceptions, have little encouragement thereto for the future, which
is alſo a great eaſe to the people.</p>
            <p>Likewiſe the making of orders upon whiſpering petitions is
provided againſt, and orders to be made only upon motion in Court, and
therein alſo the right Honourable the Lords Commiſſioners of the great
Seal, are much to be honoured for their order of notice upon motions.</p>
            <p>And the proviſions in the Ordinance concerning Mortgages are
very juſt and impartiall, and the Mortgager hath thereby a convenient time
for redemption of his Land, and the other a ſure way for recovery of his
juſt debt, which formerly he received by minute parcels, whereas his Mortgage
money was lent in groſſe, and the Mortgager often enforced to an accompt
after twenty years poſſeſſion, to his great and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tollerable
damage.</p>
            <p>Alſo the proviſion for References to be determined by three of
the ſix Maſters of the Chancery in ordinary toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, is moſt excellent;
the benefit to the people by it, is very apparent, and I my ſelf cannot but
recompt it as bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficial in my particular caſes, with gratitude for the
Juſtice by them done; and I ſhall not much inſiſt on this particular,
becauſe the grievance formerly was crying, and univerſally known and felt,
and the parties that did the wrong are deceaſed, and therefore I wiſh their
doings may be buried with them, and I have ſo much charity, as to hope they
did according to their Judgements; and it ſhall be my prayer that the
Ordinance may be punctually obſerved, and neither Maſters nor their
Regiſter, for any reſpects whatſoever, recede from their directions in
and by the Ordinance, and then it muſt be a new generation that will complain
againſt them, I have good reaſon to hope this will not, if they have done,
and ſhall perſevere to do according to the Ordinance.</p>
            <p>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:37347:6"/>It is alſo provided by the Ordinance, that the
Regiſters places ſhall not be executed by Deputies, which I hope no man
will ſpeak againſt, for what reaſon is there that ano<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther perſon
ſhould have a tribute out of the labour of men who ſpend a great part of
their age in attaining to ability in their profeſſion, and then take a
great deal of pains to do the Clients buſineſſe; Why ſhall the poor
Client pay for the Sack and Satin of another, by whom he receives no benefit,
and the allowance yielded to the labourer there, by the unneceſſary
ignorant Officer ſo mean, that if the Client had not yielded a ſupply,
there was not a ſufficient recompence for the care and labour taken by
thoſe that were Deputies formerly, but now ſtand on their own legs; and
ſure I am that if the Ordinance, as concerning the Regi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters be duly and
conſcionably obſerved, none will finde fault, but thoſe perſons who
without art or conſcience would thruſt themſelves into places they are
not able to execute.</p>
            <p>The Ordinance alſo provides well that the chief Exami<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ners do
examine all the witneſſes themſelves, and not by Deputies (as it ſeems
they do) the Ordinance notwith<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding. And if they are not able ſo to do,
either through their own incapacity, or the multiplicity of buſineſs, if
the preſent Examiners be removed, or others of ability and ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſty be
added to them, I hope it will not be a grievance worthy of any complaint.</p>
            <p>The great cry againſt the Ordinance, under colour where<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of the
caſhiered Officers have thruſt in this head of their Serpentine complaints,
is, that the Court muſt not relieve againſt new Bonds, and that Legacies
ſhall be ſued for at Law, I conceive that at the making of the Ordinance a
proviſion was intended in thoſe caſes for a relief to be had at the
Common Law, but if upon ſecond thoughts the Chancery ſhall be thought the
fitteſt Court to give relief therein, I wiſh the Suitors ſpeedy and
juſt relief there.</p>
            <p>Likewiſe the Fees are leſſened to half what they were
before, or leſſe, which I hope will be confeſſed to be an eaſe to the
people.</p>
            <p>I ſhall not grudge at the Fees given to Councell, and only
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:37347:6"/>pray that thoſe Gentlemen may have pity and compaſſion
on the poor Suitors to the Court, and that they preſſe not an evil cauſe
too farre.</p>
            <p>I could have wiſhed that ſome abler pen might have ſhewed
the uſefulneſſe of this Ordinance to the people, being my ſelf, I
confeſſe, inſufficient to do it, but by this imper<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fect diſcovery, the
perfection of that excellent conſtitution may in part appear, and the drift
of this endeavour being for the information of the people, and for their good
and advantage, I hope the imperfections thereof will be par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doned, and that the
adverſaries to the peoples welfare will not prevail againſt this Ordinance,
which was by the Su<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pream Magiſtrate of this Commonwealth, and his Councel,
with ſo great wiſdom and exactneſſe provided for their good.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="postscript">
            <head>A Poſtſcript to the Attornies of the CHANCERY.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Gentlemen,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>YOu are the perſons that are intruſted by the people, who have
occaſion of ſuit in Chancery, and the people do willingly pay you the Fees
appointed by the Ordinance as your due, you have many times made complaints of
the oppreſſion and injury done you by your late Maſters, as that it was
the only badge of villanage left in the Nation; you are now at liberty, repine
not at your deliverers, and ſeek not to return again into bondage: The
Ordinance gives you a propriety, loſe it not by your ſilence: A little of a
mans own, is better then much retained with an evil con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſcience. If the
Ordinance fall by which you have your title, you have no right to any thing
there, your Places,<pb n="10" facs="tcp:37347:7"/>your Fees are not then to be reckoned.
Joyn then your helping hand, you know better then I, and are better pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vided
with reaſons; In gratitude to his Highneſſe make them publique, and be
aſſured that if once your <hi>quondam</hi> Maſters prevail to be Lords
over you, your lives will be the moſt uncomfortable, and your ſelves the
abſoluteſt ſlaves in the world. I hope ſome of you are wiſe, let a
word therefore ſuffice.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:37347:7"/>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
